Chapter 5

Alright, so, I lied. Next chapter will likely be either a flashback to Gardy arriving in Alola or the continuation of this battle, depending on what people want.

---

Uraraka Ochako rushed down the hall, quickly preparing a breakfast of warm oatmeal and sitting on the couch, turning on the tv and flicking to the sports channel that was showing.

"And welcome, to the first Alola Pokemon League challenge," Undou Taiiku, a tall man who once played basketball at the I-Island League said, a broad smile on his face, "With me today are two people very famous people on this side of Ultra-Space, Champions Lance of the Kanto Region, and Leon of the Galar Region, both of whom have taken a long journey to be here!"

"Tell me about it!" Leon laughed in heavily accented Japanese, "Seventeen hours on the plane gets boring, even when you have the entire collection of Director Kublock to keep you busy.

"Did you fly privately, or did you take a commercial, if you don't mind me asking, Leon? I know you like to do that sometimes," Lance said, "and I can't say how good it is to see you again. I thought I'd be flying to Galar before I did!"

"Commercially. And how could I miss such a champion time, Lance?" Leon said, "I'm honestly surprised more champions aren't here, today might be the day we welcome someone into our ranks!"

"Cynthia should be here, I wonder if something actually happened in Sinnoh for her to be this late- ah, that must be a message from her now," Lance checked his phone, "She decided to stop by the Elite Four, see how they're feeling. This is big for them just as much as our competitor, I suppose. She says she'll be here soon."

"I feel a bit bad for them, honestly," Leon said, "They're all arguably worthy of the title of Champion themselves, but they chose to settle for Elite Four."

"Not everyone wants the extra responsibilities of being Champion. Look at Red, Blue and Gold, they all beat me, but they let me be the Indigo League Champion. Anyways, the first match should be starting soon, so shall we go over the competitor and his Pokemon?"

"Like people don't know, am I right?" Her dad asked, sitting down next to her and swirling a cup of coffee, "they've been marketing it for the last week. At least you haven't quieted down about it, Ochako."

"It's exciting," Ochako defended, hugging her Minior plush.

"That's right, we're here to watch Midoriya Izuku, a name I don't think anyone needs introduction to on our side of Ultra-Space, since he's the one who allowed us to make contact in the first place, take on the Elite Four and try to stake his claim as Alola's first champion! And with him, his team. Let's go over them, shall we, gentlemen?"

"It's an eclectic mix, I'd say," Lance said, as six pokemon appeared on screen, "He's definitely taking the Red-Leon style approach, if you'll forgive me for appropriating your name. A couple of strengths, but a few glaring weaknesses."

Blanket the Tyranitar
Pikakyu the Mimikyu
Gardy the Gardevoir
Mighty Chop the Machop
Dudette the Graveler
Mea the Marowak

"Ground, Ghost, Steel and Water will give him a rough time, while Poison and Fire types will be his strengths," Leon agreed, "And I'm not sure he'll be able to take advantage of those strengths, while one of the Elite Four will be able to punish his weakness to Ghost Types pretty heavily. To cover them, we have Kahuna Hala the Fighting Type specialist, Kahuna Olivia the Rock Type Specialist-

"-former Trial Captain Acerola, a Ghost Type Specialist," a new, female voice joined in and on the screen a blond haired woman with her hair over one eye spoke, settling into a chair next to Lance, "and Kahili, a friend of mine and a Flying Type Specialist. The League follows the standard where the challenger chooses which of the four to fight, with an agreed on 15 minute break between each match to patch up any injuries, but no Pokemon Center visits until after the Four have been beaten."

"Hello, Cynthia," Lance nodded, "Also worth noting is that Olivia is actually, according to our notes, a mentor to Midoriya. Has he picked his first opponent?"

"Hala," Leon said, "Makes sense, if I had anyone I was confident against with Izuku's team, it would be him. Let's switch cameras down to the arena, shall we?"

—

Izuku swallowed, sweat already wetting his brow even as Hau clapped a hand on his shoulder, Lillie and Gladion behind them, Lillie's bag full of medical supplies and Gladion just… standing there, "How are you feeling, cousin?"

"Like I'm gonna puke," Izuku said seriously as he waited for the call to the arena, "How am I supposed to do this Hau?"

"Izuku," Izuku's eyes flickered over to Gladion, "You saved our mother, you can do this. Go show them why you deserve to be Champion."

"You got this," Hau agreed as the door opened, "See you on the other side, Cousin."

"See you on the other side," Izuku said, clapping hands with Hau and walking through the door.

Stepping out of the hallway and into the arena, Izuku felt his pulse speed up with the roar of the crowd in his ear, Pikakyu tightening her grip on his hair as they did. They could do this, they would do this. If he wanted to be a hero, the first step was becoming Alola's Champion.

Across from him, Kahuna Hala stepped onto bis part of the stadium, looking over Izuku with a grandfatherly smile on his face, "Young Izuku, are you ready?"

"As I'll ever be," Izuku said, hand brushing over the six PokeBalls on his hip. Ready, steady,

Go.

"Go, Mea!"

"Poliwrath, go!"

Shoot. Mea was at a disadvantage here!

Izuku!

I know, I know!

"Waterfall!" Hala called as Izuku snapped up the Luxury Ball, calling back Mea and throwing another ball with his other hand.

Gardy, Teleport, then Ice Punch!

Gardy appeared in a flash of red energy, before immediately vanishing in a swirl of pink as the waterfall charge crashed into the barrier around the field. Gardy reappeared behind Poliwrath, pink eyes flashing as she plummeted and drove her fist into the waterfall, freezing it solid.

Psychic, then, Psycho Cut, Izuku ordered, the noises from the crowd dying as everything became the battle around him. A pink aura surrounded Poliwrath, before it was ripped from the ice and thrown high into the air. Gardy placed her hands together before pulling them apart, a pink blade forming in her hand before she swept it upwards. A pink slash came flying from the blade and struck Poliwrath, leaving a red mark across its skin.

"Now, Liquidation into Submission!" Hala ordered, and suddenly water exploded out of Poliwrath's hands and feet, sending it flying towards Gardy and catching her square in the chest. Wrapping both arms around her, it span them both into a wheel before sending them crashing into the ground so hard they skipped away from each other.

Are you alright? Do you need a potion?

I'm fine, I'm fine, Gardy staggered upwards as Hala stared at them with his arms crossed.

"I see young Gardevoir found a way to fight the way she desired despite Evolution keeping her from becoming a Galade," Hala said, before cracking a smile, "Good. Never let anything keep you from achieving your dreams!"

As Sir Wikstrom of the Kalos Elite Four says, "only you can decide to abandon the honor to be a knight", Gardy bared another sword made of psychic power, I am Gardy, proud knight and courtier of Tapu Lele, guardian of Izuku Midoriya, and I will not-

Teleport! Izuku ordered as he noticed water begin to build around Poliwrath.

"Waterfall! Liquidation!"

Gardy barely teleported out of the way of the combination of water type attacks.

Psybeam! the beam of Psychic energy hit into the Poliwrath from behind, knocking it out even as Gardy held one arm close to her side, Are you alright-?

Fine, I'm fine. I can keep fighting.

—

Ochako leaned in, watching the Pokemon stagger upwards and shake off the dizziness, even as it hugged its side slightly. The camera showed pink eyes meet green as the "Poliwrath" was pulled back into its pokeball and Hala pulled out another one.

"Are you watching that bloodsport?" Her mother clucked.

"It's not a bloodsport," Ochako defended, and a second later her dad joined in, walking over with snacks.

"It's not any worse than the UA Sports Fest, dear. Yes, the Pokemon get hurt, but they get patched up just fine afterwards."

"I still don't like it, it's like dogfighting," her Mom said, even as she settled down next to them.

"Is he not recalling her?" Leon asked, "Not even for a quick patch job?

"Bad move," Lance said, "She has the Type Advantage, yes, but as those injuries show, a good trainer can get around that. And Elite Four members are, by definition, good trainers.

"Don't be so hard, we don't know what's going through their heads right now," Cynthia said, " It's like trying to judge what Red's doing at any particular moment in time.

"True, whatever conversation they're having, we're not tuned into it," Leon said, " That's the problem with Psychics and Psychic types, innit?

"He should still be pushing her to take a break, even if it's just, as you said, a patch job. I've taken Submissions from Bruno's Pokemon before, she has to be hurting."

—

Gardy hid the wince at the pain in her arm, aware that if she showed any sign of weakness now, at this moment, Izuku would call her back. She didn't want to be called back, she wanted to keep on fighting, show the world that she was the best knight in Alola.

Ok, so she was the only knight in Alola as far as she knew, it wasn't like there were hundreds hounding for that position, but that was beside the point.

"Primeape, come on out!" Hala called, and out of the PokeBall came a mass of rage and violence in the shape of a furry ape. Muscles bulged as It lowered itself and-

Crush, Maim, Kill, Break, Shatter, Destroy-

"Rage Fist!" Hala called, and suddenly Primeape was in Gardy's guard, a fist covered in purple flames smashing into her chest and sending her flying backwards faster than she could blink.

There was no warning, no psychic pulse beyond the constant, overwhelming desire to inflict harm on her.

Psycho Cut-

Crush, Maim, Kill-

Gardy created a second blade of psychic power as Primeape appeared in her guard again, dodging a second Rage Fist and launching a slash, only for it to miss in turn.

"Keep using Rage Fist!" Hala said, and Gardy was left backpedaling from the rapid Ghost-Type punches.

Teleport, then Psybeam!

Gardy vanished from the spo-

"Pursuit!"

Damnation.

Space warped, and suddenly she was being chokeslammed into the ground by the enraged Primeape.

"Now, finish this-"

"Gardy! Psychic on Primeape!" Izuku ordered with something resembling desperation in his voice. Gardy grabbed the Pokemon and threw it away as fast as she could.

It wasn't fast enough.

"Rage Fist!"

An explosion of purple grey flames covered her, and she struggled to stay awake long enough to slam Primeape into the ground. Once he was there, she tipped over backwards and blacked out.

—

Ochako watched the beautiful green pokemon crumple gracefully, gripping her Dad's hand like a lifeline as Izuku raised as black and gold PokeBall and called it back. He pressed it to his lips gently, mumbling something the cameras couldn't pick up and then he looked up, saying something in Alolan. The Pokemon in his hair, Pikakyu, lifted up gently and landed on the ground in the arena, staring at where the badly battered monkey was rising and burning with anger.

"See, that's what I was talking about, most Elite Four level trainers keep a silver bullet for Types that should have the advantage. I'd focus on evolving Primeape into an Annihilape going forwards," Lance said, "Have a real silver bullet against psychic types.

"Yeah, but it's gonna feel the hurt now, I betcha, Leon said, "Because it just took a decent pummeling and Hala doesn't seem to be recalling it either."

"True," Leon nodded, "Thoughts, Cynthia?"

"I'm honestly surprised Izuku didn't start with- oh. Check the notes on Pikakyu," Cynthia said.

"Oh, all three of the other commentators said.

—

Pikakyu's growled, a loud, clicking noise as she left Izuku's head and landed on the ground in the arena, staring down the Primeape eyes glowing red.

"Play Rough," Izuku said, and Pikakyu exploded into motion, rushing towards the other pokemon in an explosion of speed. Pink energy gathered around two of her arms and she began to absolutely pummel the hell out of Primeape faster than it could respond.

How dare it hurt one of her friends, her family!?

"Rage Fist!" Pikakyu twisted around the punch, her smaller frame letting her twist around the attack.

"Keep Playing Rough!" Izuku called, and Pikakyu did exactly that, continuing thrashing the other Pokemon until it finally collapsed, letting it drop on the ground and staring at Hala.

Send out another, let them see how good a Pokemon she was. Gardy had given it her all, it was only fair that she do the same.[/I]

Chapter 6

Bakugo Katsuki sat in the VIP section of the arena, trying to hide his frustration at the fact that he was here at all because stupid Deku had decided to invite his family to this stupid tournament thing. And his parents had agreed to come for some stupid reason.

"Izuku's two to one," Tsutsumi Kaina, aka Lady Nagant, a fuckin' pro hero who had been assigned to be Deku's bodyguard, because he deserved one of those apparently, said. Her knee was jumping up and down as she ran a hand down the beak of her giant toucan pokemon, "He's gonna win this match!"

Fuckin' so? What did it matter if he won this whole contest with his stupid pets? That wasn't real strength, why was everyone acting like if Deku won this he would be the strongest person in Alola. That was acting like All Might's manager was stronger than All Might! It didn't make sense!

"IIIIZZUUUKKKKUUUU!" Aunty Inko cried as the tiny pink Pokemon she had, which had a stone in its pouch like an egg, ran around her with a mop to clean up the tears, occasionally stopping to pull out a futile tissue and hand it to Inko before returning to the process of running around and cleaning up the floor.

"Happiny!" It took a second to stop and thrust a fist into the air, staring down at Izuku. Then a particularly large splash of water got its attention and it went right back to mopping up Aunty Inko's tears.

"Go, Crabominable!" The fatass Deku was fighting, "Hala" threw out one of the balls as he pulled back in the monkey and out came a furry crab, "Ice Punch!"

"Return, Pikakyu!" Deku snapped up a ball, red light pulling the small thing back into it as he tossed out another ball, "Mea, Fire Punch!'

The crowd roared as the animal wearing a skull came out, pulling back the fist holding a flaming bone and punching forwards, the green flames on either end of the bone coming together at the fist and igniting it. Ice and fire met in the middle of the stadium, causing an explosion of steam that caused Hala's robes and Izuku's stupid sleeveless jacket to whip in the air as they both dug their feet into the ground and refused to budge.

"They're really going at it, aren't they?" Katsuki whipped around as a boy a couple years older than them stepped into the VIP section, holding one of those damn gimmicky pokemon phones that were all the rage on this side of Ultra Space to the electronic lock before dropping it and letting it float in behind them.

"Considering the amount of times I had to watch Kukui's League Challenge back when he was a brat," Nagant said, drawing a laugh from Inko, "I think I would be firing a Beak Blast at the arena right now if he wasn't. Hello, Gladion."

"Hello, Ms. Tsutsumi, Mrs. Midoriya, uh…? I don't think we've met, you three?"

"I'm Bakugo Mitsuki, and these are my husband, Masaru, and son Katsuki."

"Nice to meet you. Excuse me, Happiney, just trying to get to a seat. Come out, Silvally," Out of a ball came a dog with a wing on its head, staring down at the arena. It stared down at the arena as Emo Cut began to run a hand through its feathers and fur, "I'm Gladion, I'm a friend of Izuku."

"Where's Lillie?" Inko asked, wiping tears from her eyes as she did.

"Down in the locker room, she wanted to act as his medicinal support if anything went really wrong. She doesn't like watching Pokemon Battles anyways," Gladion said.

—

Mea landed on the ground, catching her bone and beginning to rhythmically tap it against the ground as she waited for the steam to fade. In the background she heard Izuku start to pace and smiled, if a bit sadly, under her bone mask.

"Fire Blast!" Izuku finally called, and Mea brought her burning bone up to her mouth and breathed in, before spitting out a giant daimonji of green flames into the mist, forcing it to disperse and revealing Crabominable and Hala having struck a pose.

"Shoot!" Izuku snapped, pulling out a container of crystals and quickly picking one, slotting it into his Z Power Ring and crossing his arms in front of himself. Z Energy exploded like a raging inferno around his body, before flowing into Mea as she struck a pose.

"I am the Kahuna of Melemele Island, Young Izuku," Hala called, Z Energy flowing from himself to Crabominable as he continued the dance, "That means, at one point in the past I too went on a Island Challenge journey! Did you really think I only knew one Z-Move?"

"Of course not," Izuku said, continuing their dance alongside Mea, "Now, Mea! Inferno-"

Mea raised her club to her mouth, breathing in until her ghostly ribcage felt like it would crack. At the same time, ice began to build around Crabominable. Hala swept an arm outwards, "Subzero-"

"-Overdrive!" Mea breathed out, a miniature sun exploding into existence in front of her and building until she finally fired it at Crabominable.

"-Slammer!" Ice exploded forwards, crashing against the Inferno Overdrive and warring with it until finally both Z-moves exploded, coating their halves of the field in fire and ice. Mea cut through the resulting steam with her bone, staring at Crabominable as it shattered the ice that formed over it, the arena now evenly divided into fire and ice sections.

"Fire Blast!" Izuku called, and Mea shot out another Daimonji, which crashed home and staggered the Crabominable backwards, "Flare Blitz on its underbelly!"

Green flames ignited all along Mea's body and she kicked off, rushing forwards and gripping her bone like one of Gardy's swords. She hoped her son was watching this, wherever he was.

The flaming bone crashed into Crabominable's soft underbelly, sending it collapsing back, unconscious.

"Mea, return!"

—

Katsuki's jaw dropped as the arena turned into something out of an anime, half burning with fire and the other half coated with ice. That was… that was like something Endeavor would do! Why were these pokemon listening to losers like Deku when they could do something like that.

"So, we finally see the famous Z-Moves of Alola," one of the talking heads said, the TV in the back flicking back to them, it was the one with red hair swept back, wearing a cape like he was some kind of Hero. None of them were Heroes, they were just… just riding on the coattails of their Pokemon! "And it seems to have reshaped the battlefield around them."

"It's definitely an impressive move, Lance," the one wearing a hat said, taking it off to run a hand through his hair, "I can see why it's compared to Dynamax and Mega Evolution."

"Otherwise, I don't have much to say about that particular round," the pretty blonde said, "Izuku sent out the Pokemon with the clear advantage and won. If I had to guess-

"Pikakyu, I chose you!"

"Hariyama, your turn!"

-We'll likely see something of a sweep from here on out. Pikakyu has the advantage."

—

"Pikakyu, don't rough them up too hard," Pikakyu flashed Izuku a thumbs up as Izuku pulled out another pokeball and sent out the unconscious Gardy, before fishing out a full restore and beginning to apply it to Gardy's wounds while Pikakyu focused on Hariyama.

"Fire Punch!" Hala called out, and Pikakyu dodged to the side, letting the move go wide before using Play Rough to bat Hariyama back, "Fire Punch and Heavy Slam repeatedly! Don't let it escape!"

"Keep Playing Rough, don't let him hit you!" Izuku called, cracking open a revive and wafting the crystal under Gardy's nose as Pikakyu launched into a storm of Play Roughs, flying around Hariyama's bulk so the Fire Punches and Heavy Slams missed it until finally Hariyama tipped forwards unconscious at the exact same time Gardy jerked upright with a gasp, "Slowly, slowly, stand up slowly, Gardy, you were unconscious for fifteen minutes or so."

I'm fine, I'm fine. I can fight, Gardy forced herself up, Pikakyu, switch out for me.

…Don't wanna.

You'll get your spotlight when we fight Acerola, let me show I can fight with the best!

…Fine.

Pikakyu retreated as Gardy rushed the field, landing on top of Izuku's head and beginning to sulk until-

Aguav berry!

Pikakyu snagged the offered berry from Izuku, beginning to munch away at the berry happily.

"Thank you, Pikakyu. You know Gardy's been looking forward to this," Izuku said softly as Gardy stared down the Bewear. Pikakyu hummed, focused more on the steady supply of her favorite berries Izuku was giving her over the fight about to happen.

—

Katsuki scoffed as the green and white pokemon took the field again, "What's he doing? That weakling already lost once."

"So?" Nagant said, "I know Gardy, she's only going to be more determined to win and prove that she's a good knight now that she went down once. That's just how she is, it's her version of being a Hero."

"Heroes don't lose," Katsuki scoffed again, "That's why they're heroes, they win."

"Do you really think that?" Nagant said, "That Heroes never lose? Ever? How childish can you get."

Katsuki froze, before turning towards her, "What?"

"Heroes lose, Kid. We lose a lot, we fail a lot. I was a real big failure of a Hero before I was assigned to be Izuku's bodyguard. Heroes don't always win, we always try to win, but that doesn't mean we succeed."

"Nobody wins every time," Emo Cut said, "I've lost to Izuku more times than I can count, and Izuku's lost before too. The key is winning when it counts."

"You're not strong," Katsuki snapped, "You just use your pokemon-"

"I ran away from home at 11, I survived until I was 13 without help. I'm currently running one of the biggest companies in the world. Tell me, what have you done to judge what strength is?" Emo Cut stood up, ice filling the room as his Pokemon tugged at the back of his sweatshirt, "You're just a kid who's never done anything in his life, but you think you're smart enough to unilaterally decide what strength is, brat?"

"Gladion, he's just a kid, he doesn't know what he's talking about," Aunty Inko sniffed, taking a tissue from Happiney.

"Exactly, he's just a kid, and he's saying me and Izuku aren't strong because we train pokemon. Have you ever trained a Pokemon, kid? Ever had a Rockruff about to evolve maul your arm?" Emo Cut shoved up his sleeve, showing bite scars along his arm, "have you ever sync your aura to a Pokemon to the point you feel the pain they do? Had a move gone too far and burned you, or frozen you? How about have a sandstorm bite at your skin as you fought with everything you had? Being a Pokemon trainer isn't some walk in the park, kid. It's a hard job, and you're disrespecting everyone who has devoted their lives to the profession by calling us weak. So do us all a favor, sit down, shut up, and cheer for Izuku, because he clearly cares about you enough to invite you to his crowning as Champion of Alola."

"I…" Katsuki through himself into the chair, huffing, "Fine, whatever. Loser."

The last word was muttered under his breath, even as chills crossed his back and he focused on Izuku, noticing the faded and fresh scars along his arms for the first time. What had caused those?

—

Gardy teleported behind the Bewear, forming a blade of Psychic energy and driving it into its back.

"Brutal Swing!" Gardy ducked under the full force swing from Bewear, eyes glowing as she picked it up with her psychic energy and lifted it high into the air before slamming it into the ground. Red energy formed around the crystal on her chest as she drew another sword and rushed in, launching a barrage of Psycho Cuts at their chest.

"Brutal Swing and don't let up!" Bewear was suddenly in Gardy's Guard (that joke wasn't as funny since she changed her name), Dark type energy glowing as it brought down both arms. Both hit Gardy straight in the shoulders as Gardy thrust the created an Aura Sphere and blasted back Bewear.

Draining Kiss, Izuku ordered, and Gardy teleported behind behind Bewear, planting a soft, draining kiss on its check, and then drove a Psycho Cut into its chest, dropping in to the ground unconscious.

"YES!" Izuku cheered, rushing out onto the pitch and tackling Gardy into a hug she quickly returned, sending out Mea so she and Pikakyu could join in the hug.

"And with that, Izuku Midoriya has beat his first Elite Four member. There will be a fifteen minute break to fix any damage done to the stadium and allow Izuku to patch up any injuries, then we'll move onto the next member, Khaili."

"Well done, young Izuku, Guardy, Mea, Pikakyu, you all did well," Hala said, walking towards them, As a celebration of your victory, I have a gift for you."

He opened up his hand, revealing a marble sized crystal on a small rope. Gardy immediately felt psychic energy flow between her and it the minute she lay eyes on it.

is that- Gardy asked.

"A Gardevoirite, from a friend in Kalos," Hala said, "I know you have your reservation about Mega Evolution, Young Izuku, but I figured if you could Mega Evolve someone that can tell you the stories are false, you can use it with confidence. You might not use it in this tournament, because I'm going to assume you'll prefer your Z-Moves, but you never know when having something like this as an ace will come in handy."

—

Next chapter is a Flashback
No, "Guardy" in Hala's listing is not a misspelling.

Chapter 7

I'm in a bad mood, have a chapter.

---

"You're sure you're alright?" Izuku urged as Gardy swallowed an oran berry before taking a long swig of water from the offered water bottle A sigh echoed in his and Lillie's head as she dropped the half empty bottle and took another oran berry from Lillie.

I'm fine, and the chances of me coming out for the next couple of rounds is minimal anyways, Izuku, Gardy argued.

"Sixty seconds," a head popped into the room and all three inhabitants nodded as Gardy pulled on the Gardevoirite, offering a soft smile at Izuku's disapproving look.

A little pain never hurt anyone, Zuzu.

"That is, by definition, not true," Izuku snorted but held out her Luxury Ball, letting Gardy shrink into it and walked out into the hall leading into the stadium. The crew member held up ten seconds, and Izuku nodded.

9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1

Go.

Izuku jogged into the repaired arena waving at the crowd as, at the same time, a pretty young woman in a golf uniform stepped out into the arena. They met in the middle, and she offered him a handshake that Izuku took with a swallow of spit.

"Kahili," she said, before offering him a calming smile.

"Izuku Midoriya," Izuku returned, offering a smile that hopefully didn't show how nervous he was still feeling.

"Let's give them a good show, Ok?" She said, letting go of his hand and walking towards the other side of the arena from Izuku. Izuku's hand brushed the balls at his side, and he felt one shake violently. Ok, he got the message.

Drawing the Luxury ball off his hip, he expanded it as Kahili did the same with her Ultra ball and put it on the ground, pressing her golf club against it. Finally, both moved as one, Izuku throwing the ball while Kahili drove hers.

"Go, Mighty Chop!"

"Let's do this, Skarmory!"

Out of Izuku's ball came a two foot tall mass of muscle and gray skin crouching down. He stood to his full, rather unimpressive height, and cracked his neck and shot a devilish grin at the iron bird that had been sent out across from him.

"Ready? Begin!" The judge waved his hand, and both trainers immediately called out their moves, "Thunder Punch, Mighty!"

"Spikes, Skarmory."

"Don't let him put them down, Mighty!"

"Good luck with that," Kahili called, "Skarmory can fly over at over 190 miles per hour. Skarmory, the moment you're done with Spikes, use Steel Wing."

—

Mighty grinned as he came out of the PokeBall, stretching his arms and cracking his neck. Maybe this battle would be worth evolving for! The Elite Four were supposed to be the strongest trainers in Alola, right?

"Thunder Punch, Mighty!" The Boss called and Mighty lowered himself again, leg muscles bulging as he built up power in his fist. Finally, the noise of chirping echoed across the arena and he took off at the Skarmory flying across the arena and dropping spikes. The flying type Pokemon sped up as Mighty got closer to it, and Mighty lunged upwards, driving a crackling fist into their underbelly.

Or at least he should have. Instead, he clipped the tail, sending the bird flipping through the air and crashing into the ground. Mighty heard an irritated sigh from the other trainer, followed by a quick order.

"Skarmory, Steel Wing," before Mighty could move, the flying type was in his guard, slamming into him and sending him skidding back and biting his feet into the spikes.

"Revenge to the skull," the boss ordered, and Mighty brought down his fist with thunderous force. Skarmory smashed into the ground, shaking his head to shake off the stunning blow, "And Seismic Toss."

Mighty threw his arms around Skarmory, hoisting him into the air and leaping into the air, throwing him straight into the ground.

"Steel Wing," the woman ordered, and suddenly Skarmory was flying straight up and drilling into Mighty. Mighty went flying higher into the air as Skarmory continued further into the air, "and Steel Wing!"

"Vital Throw!" Mighty braced himself in mid air as best as he could and felt the Steel Wing slam into him. Falling into a side slam, they both smashed into the ground. After a few seconds to gather his breath, Mighty rolled up and planted his foot onto the unconscious Skarmory and thrust his fist into the air, drinking in the roar of the crowd as he went.

"Mighty, can you keep fighting?" Boss asked softly. Mighty breathed in, before nodding his head, falling to his knee and reaching for the belt around his waist.

And with as much pride as he could, he threw off the Everstone around his waist and began to evolve as the roar of the crowd reached a crescendo.

—

Riolu watched Machop slam into the ground alongside the bird as Dad made himself a bowl of soup, sitting down next to him once it was finished and putting a bowl of blueberries in front of him. Dad glanced up at the TV and watched Machop stagger to its feet and throw a fist into the air.

"Hmm, Mighty looks tired," he said.

"Olu?" Riolu said, tilting his head and blinking up at Dad. Did he know that pokemon?

"What's up, buddy?" Dad asked, and Riolu pointed at the screen.

"Riolu, olu, ri?" Riolu said, trying to get his question across.

"Do I know them?" Dad asked, and Riolu nodded, "I met his trainer once. It was an… interesting experience. It was actually the same day I got you."

"Ri?" Really?

"Yeah, he was the one who gave me your egg," Dad's lips split into one of his signature grins, "It was a really weird day, I was expecting a signature signing or something but… nope, egg. He was told to give you to someone he could trust to do the right thing with you, and I guess in a little kid's head, that meant me. I was a little startled at first, ya know?"

"Olu?"

"Well, you know, I got enemies, and I wasn't sure what I was gonna do with you, but then you hatched and everything just sort of… clicked, if that makes any sense? I knew I was gonna keep you, because you were just hatched and I could already feel the good in your heart. I knew you were gonna do good, and try to help people whether I kept you or not. Because that's who you are."

"Riolu!" Riolu said, pride in his voice as he popped a blueberry into his mouth. Of course he would help people, that was who he was. He liked fighting, but he really liked it when people were happy to be safe afterwards!

"And that's, oh, is he evolving?" Yagi Toshinori said, attention suddenly drawn to the TV. Yagi Riolu snapped his head to the screen, where the Machop was covered in white light and growing taller, bigger, stronger. Finally, with a burst of flexing muscles, the light was forced off of him and he roared out.

"MACHOKE!"

—

AN

So, um, there is no easy way to say this.

OHA(P)M may be going on Indefinite Hiatus. Not because I want to, I love this story and want to continue writing it as soon as it becomes tenable, but because all of my stories may be going on Indefinite Hiatus.

I don't want to go into details, because it's personal and frankly (and sorry for the rudeness) none of your business, but I may be in a state of being incapable of writing soon. I'll work and write until it becomes untenable, but there is the very real possibility I will have restricted, if any, access to anything electronic for a-

Ah, fuck it, I'm not one for beating around the bush. I might be hospitalized/institutionalized for a bit, and that obviously means restricted access to electronics. I don't want that to happen, and I will do everything in my power to avoid it, but depending on what my psychiatrist decides the decision may be out of my hands. My mental health comes first, and if he decides that institutionalization is in my best interest, I'm gonna trust him.

So yeah, I can't promise anything. I don't know what my future holds.